LYDIA TSANG

Data Analyst & Business Professional

Contact Details

****939-488-2141

≤wmltsang@gmail.com

inlinkedin.com/in/lydiatsang

https://github.com/wmltsang

https://public.tableau.com/profile/wai.mai.lydia.tsang#!/

ABOUT ME

I am a curious and cheerful data analyst specializing in the business field. I love problem-solving, and I enjoy manipulating and visualizing data to provide better business insights. I also have exceptional administration skillsets and a solid background in customer services, which has cultivated me as an active listener to understand problems that are keys to be a successful data analyst.

EDUCATION

Nashville Software School | Jan 2021

Data Analytics Certification

Texas Wesleyan University | 2019

Master of Business Administration, Health Care (GPA: 4.00) Honors: Beta Gamma Sigma

The Hong Kong Polytechnic University | 2013

Bachelor of Science in Hotel Management

DATA EXPERIENCE

Nashville Software School | Jan 2021

Data Analyst

Six months of project experience using real-world data utilizing data exploratory and explanatory analysis applying business intelligence tools and programming languages to drive business resolution in excellency; Strong business background to understand the data and apply fundamental statistical knowledge for logical reasoning in problem-solving; Familiar with the agile process for group projects and used GitHub and Kanban board for effective collaboration

Lahman Baseball (PostgreSQL)

https://github.com/NSS-Data-Analytics-Cohort-3/lahaman-baseball-datasciencewarrior

Analyzed all the colleges in the State of Tennessee and used several metrics to find out the college had had the most success in the major leagues

- Conducted an external analysis to define success, found the right metrics to extract data, and used CTEs, SQL
 joins, where clause to filter for TN colleges
- Calculated metrics with numbers of major leagues players and total salary each college for comparisons among years, and concluded that the University of Tennessee had the most success and used supporting horizontal bar charts

UN Data Analysis (Python)

https://github.com/NSS-Data-Analytics-Cohort-3/un-data-wmltsang

Conducted a correlation analysis of GDP per capita and internet usage among countries

- Examined dataset information, datatype, and performed data cleaning. Then, merged two datasets with the correct merge
- Created scatter plots to identify positive relationships between internet usage and GDP per capita between years
- Examined data distribution using histograms and used time-series on the x-axis in facet grids to show variable trends among different countries

Indeed Data Analyst Jobs (PowerBI)

https://github.com/wmltsang/PowerBI-Workshop

Offered career insights of data analyst jobs in the US

 Calculated employee's satisfaction ratings, rankings of industry demand, required skillsets, size of companies, and common job titles Created a dashboard to show a summary of findings and provided filters for selecting desired states, hierarchy settings to allow data breakdown

WORK EXPERIENCE

Department of Human Service | Feb 2017- Present

Administrative Assistant II

Administers numerous services by connecting Tennesseans to employment, education, and support services

- Excel at multi-tasking meeting tight deadlines for executives and teams delivering effective business outcomes managing more than 4000 active facilities
- Active initiator of making administrative and procedural decisions that can address potential issues for a monthly average of 2000 checks
- Compile the commissioner's dashboard data and continuously monitor unit performance, ensuring team performance timeliness completion of 5 days
 - Use Excel and Tableau extracted from a SQL database for creating team key performance indicators and data visualization
- Improve the reporting process in incident reporting and background checks coordinating interdepartmental efforts to transform process electronically, enhancing process productivity across 95 counties in Tennessee
- Maintain data system and organize records (improve productivity, reduce costs and save money with 28-cubic feet filings)
- Process invoices and troubleshoot record mismatch by managing state funding over 3 million that are essential for fiscal cost management and accuracy of financial outflow for all 12 departmental divisions
- Provide exceptional coordination and communication for all 12 divisions and external stakeholders that help fostering positive work relationships and ensure unit goals are on track

Gaylord Opryland Resort & Convention Center | Sep 2015-Jan 2017

Team Lead - Guest Service Agent and Trainer

One of the largest hotels in the world providing first-class customer service owned by Marriott International

- Active listener providing top-notch client service and daily problem solver handling customer complaints that
 effectively and economically solved customers' problems of daily average 1000 check-ins
- Executed 80 thousand sales and financial transactions daily that contributed to maximizing revenues and resulted in higher guest satisfaction level
- Provided training, coaching, and support to onboard and assign workflows for junior employees, which
 increased employees' engagement and performance productivity
 - Successfully trained more than 60 employees onboard

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- •Data Analytics: Python, SQL, Tableau, Power BI
- Microsoft: Advanced Excel (Power Pivot, Vlookup), Word,
 PowerPoint, and Outlook
- Others: Remote Work/ Communication, Documentation, GitHub, GitBash

LANGUAGES

- English (Proficient)
- Cantonese (Native)
- Mandarin (Proficient)
- German (Intermediate)
- Korean (Basic)
- Spanish (Basic)

CERTIFICATIONS

SQL Fundamentals Track

Data Camp, Credential ID:129290

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Army and Air Force Exchange Service | Customer Service | Representative | Fort Campbell, May – Sep 2015

Best Western Grand Hotel | Customer Service Receptionist | Hong Kong, Nov 2014 – Jan 2015

The Hotel Adlon Kempinski | Internship Berlin, International Trade Fair | Customer Service/Translator Düsseldorf | Germany, Aug 2013 – Aug 2014

Hotel & Exhibitions Customer Service Part-timer | Hong Kong, 2011-2012

Management Internship | Shanghai China, Jul - Dec 2010